Senior IT Professional

Core Competencies

General

- Resource Management (Team)
- Delivery Management (Projects)
- Environment Cost Management
- Identity Access Management
- Security Compliance Standards
- Risk & Vulnerability Management
- Cloud Security & Governance

Google Cloud Platform (GCP) Cloud

- Governance Implementation
- Integration of Security controls and services
- Remediation of risks & vulnerabilities

Microsoft Azure

- Azure Workshops
- Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework
- Azure Identity services
 (Azure AD & Azure Domain Services)
- Migration (laaS)
 (Azure Site Recovery, Azure Migrate)
- Innovation (SaaS & PaaS)
 (Azure Domain Services, Virtual Desktop, SQL)
- Cloud Services Integration
 (Microsoft Defender for Cloud, Azure Policy, Automation, Log Analytics, Monitoring)

Technical Highlights

Azure Foundation, Landing Zone, Security & Governance

Support a global organization through optimizing their existing Azure environment consisting of over 930 subscriptions with limited governance and security applied. The process began by leading an Azure Workshop identifying options available to align with organizational needs, requirements, in adherence with regulatory guidelines, and best practices. Following the Client's approval of the design plan, I worked collaboratively with the Client's team to implement the framework and developed automation to deploy and maintain the desired configurations. Upon the conclusion, the Client successfully passed multiple compliance audits and extended the engagement to migrate all systems and services from its data centers to Azure adopting a Cloud-First strategy.

Azure Migration

American Cancer Society desired to reduce their overall IT infrastructure. As their contract with various data centers were expiring, they used the opportunity to drive an initiative to migrate ALL services to Azure within 12 weeks. The Client already had an established Azure environment, so the process began with a platform assessment, reviewing services and features, and implementing new configurations. The initial scope consisted of over 700 servers, following an in-depth server assessment, we were able to consolidate these or migrate to cloud services effectively reducing the scope to approximately 350 servers. Once the migration plan was completed, I lead the technical delivery team through completion of the migration in 9 weeks.

Discovery Script

Developed and maintain a PowerShell script which streamlines the discovery and audit process of an Azure environment by capturing configurations and settings for key features and services then exports the results into an Excel workbook. This serves to document the beginning and end states of the environment while providing a vital reference during the engagements. ©

Senior IT Professional

Experience

2018/10 – Present Redapt, Inc. (Attunix)

Modern Datacenter Team Lead | Delivery Manager and Cloud Solutions Architect

The Modern Datacenter (MDC) is a team within the Professional Services Delivery division of Redapt that assists organizations adopt the public cloud and modernize infrastructure by designing secure and scalable environments. As the Team Lead, my personal duties and responsibilities include:

Delivery Manager

- Responsible for leading the individual contributors driving successful delivery execution through team preparedness, precision delivery, coordinating utilization, and ensuring high customer satisfaction from the services delivered.
- Interview and hire appropriate technical individuals to support objectives. Collaborate with internal teams in workforce capacity planning and placement.
- Develop and connect with resources through 1-1's, leading team meetings, mentoring, and providing guidance to achieve organizational and individual goals.
- Responsible for the planning, prioritization, translating, communicating, and implementing the broader business strategy at the team level while fostering a culture of inclusivity and growth mindset.
- Collaborate with the account team to understand customer/partner requirements and constraints.
 Guides the team on understanding customer/partner requirements by providing resources as needed.
- Supports project managers and direct reports on projects by bridging gaps in resources. Plans the team's work and responds to changing priorities.
- Guide the team in operational excellence and hold resources accountable for deliverables. Identify
 opportunities for collaboration with other teams. Ensure an adherence to services and delivery
 processes. Serve as an executive sponsor for strategic projects.
- Proactively report/anticipate issues, analyze situations and facilitate the process of resolving complex issues in collaboration with account-aligned teams. Engage with internal teams to address customer/partner feedback to identify and contribute to the drivers of satisfaction and dissatisfaction, identify the root cause, and establish recovery actions to improve experience.

Pre-Sales

- Represent Redapt on sales calls to assist in determining client needs, requirements for delivery, establishment of expectations then drafting applicable Statements of Work.
 - o 2021, directly responsible for 47 opportunities representing \$4.6M in revenue.
 - o 2020, directly responsible for 77 opportunities representing \$4.4M in revenue.
- Represent Redapt with Partners (Microsoft, Google, Intel, NetApp, Rapid7, etc.) to manage potential opportunities and align existing services or work to develop new services.
- Development of service offerings:
 - Responsible for expanding service offerings to include Identity Management, Active Directory Migrations/Consolidations, Identity Modernization through cloud integration, and Exchange to 365 migrations. As of 2022/01, these services have yielded \$4.6M in revenue.

Senior IT Professional

- Responsible for developing new service offerings to include Security & Governance, establishing partner relationships, training technical resources, and working with marketing and sales teams.
 As of 2022/01, these services have yielded \$1.9M in revenue.
- Following the impacts of the Coronavirus (COVID-19), the Modern Datacenter worked with partners to develop a partner funded service offering to reengage with Clients. Through this, I assisted with the establishment of a Redapt Cloud Adoption Framework offering including the development of its engagement outline, determination of deliverables, and led 32 successful engagements over a 3-month period. This service performs an analysis on an existing cloud environment to provide organizations with the insight needed to better understand the current security posture, costs, and provide guidance towards improvement. As of 2022/01, this initiative has yielded \$7.5M in additional follow-on engagements across all Redapt divisions.

Technical Lead

Serve as the lead architect on large-scale engagements and as the technical point of escalation for all Modern Datacenter engagements. Specific responsibilities for this role include:

- Lead discovery sessions and design workshops iterating the client through Microsoft's Cloud Adoption Framework leveraging Zero-Trust and Lean Methodology concepts. Review Azure services and features to determine applicable integration to meet the organization's business needs and requirements.
- Architect and design a comprehensive architecture design (Azure Landing Zone/Platform Foundation) leveraging applicable components of Microsoft's Enterprise-Scale Model. Develop infrastructure-as-code (PowerShell, ARM Templates, Azure Blueprints)
- Collaborate with clients to determine security and governance requirements to align with organizational goals and regulatory compliances.
- Actively lead and support delivery resources through the delivery process.
- Responsible for documentation and lead Client handoff.
- Collaborate with team to determine process improvements and define next steps for the Client.

2011/12 – 2018/10 CGI Inc. (CGI Group Inc.)

Senior Consultant | Domain Lead, Enterprise Solutions Architect

- Managed the cloud and domain teams consisting of Windows, Unix, networking and database engineers. Served as the technical lead on projects, managed solution delivery, and established processes and procedures to ensure standardization of services.
- Represented CGI remotely and on-site with clients; evaluating their infrastructure and working
 with clients to design solutions to meet their individual business requirements. Solutions were
 environment agnostic including physical, virtual (VMware), cloud (Microsoft Azure and Amazon
 Web Services), and hybrid cloud infrastructures. Each solution aligned with business strategies
 through Lean methodologies while adhering to ITIL and ISO/IEC processes and meeting governing
 security compliance requirements.

2001/03 - 2021/09 U.S. Army

2003-2021 – 246th South Carolina Army National Guard Band - Columbia, SC

2002-2003 - 116th Georgia National Guard Army Band - Ellenwood, GA

2001-2002 – 93rd U.S. Army Reserve Signal Corp - Ft. Gordon, GA

Senior IT Professional

Education

2008	Bachelors of Science Information Systems, Strayer University
2019	Professional Cloud Architect, Google
2019	Metasploit Pro Certified Specialist; Rapid7
2016	Understanding Cisco Cloud Fundamentals, Global Knowledge
2016	VMware vSphere ICM 6 (VCP6-DCV), Stanly Community College
2016	Azure Master Class, Microsoft
2015	Effective Leader, EDGE Development Program
2015	Cisco Data Center Unified Computing Implementation (DCUCI)
2014	IT Infrastructure Library (ITIL) v3
2010	U.S. Army Warrior Leader Course (WLC)
2008	Hacker Techniques, Exploits & Incident Handling (SEC504), SANS
2007	Certified Systems Administrator, Diplomatic Security Training Center
2003	Associates of Technology Information Systems, Ogeechee Technical College
2001	U.S. Army Adjutant General School (AIT)